Guide to the Veranus A. Moore Papers, 1836-1958
Moore, Veranus A. papers, 1836-1958
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Miscellaneous Family and Friends - Negatives (Box 43, Folder 5)
________. "The teeth of the horse as affected by age, part III." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 116, September 1900.
__________. "The teeth of cattle and sheep as affected by age." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 118, November 1900.
________. "The most common irregularities of the teeth of the horse, part I." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 119, December 1900.
__________. "The most common irregularities of the teeth of the horse, part II." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 119, January 1901.
McEachern, Donald. "A study of the morbid anatomy of hearts from patients dying with hyperthyroidism." Reprinted from Bulletin of the Johns Hopkins Hospital, May 1931.
McEachran, Duncan. "Veterinary sanitary science: a brief historical sketch of early history of live stock quarantine in Canada." Dominion of Canada Department of Agriculture
McGrew, T.F. "American Breeds of Fowls: I-The Plymouth Rock." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1901.
________. "American Breeds of Fowls: II-The Wyandotte." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1901.
McWhorter, V.O. "The sheep-killing dog." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin, 16 April 1915.
Meleney, Frank L. "Infections of skin and the subcutaneous tissue." Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, October 1930.
Melvin, A.D. "Report of the chief of the bureau of animal industry." U.S. Department of Agriculture annual report, 22 December 1906.
Menyhert, S. "Allatbiztositas." VIII. Nemzetkozi Allatorvosi Kongresszus Budapest, 1905.
Mercer, William Fairchild. "The development of the wings in the lepidoptera." Reprinted from Journal of New York Entomological Society, March 1900.
Minot, Charles Sedgwick. "Gegen das gonotom." Reprinted from Anatomischer Anzeiger, ca. 1893.
Minot, Charles Sedgwick and C.B. Davenport, et al. "The relation of the American Society of Naturalists to other scientific socities." Reprinted from Science, 21 February 1902.
__________. "The embroyological basis of pathology." Reprinted from the Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 28 March 1901.
________. "Structural plan of the human brain." Reprinted from Popular Science Monthly, July 1893.
Mohler, John R. "Infectiveness of milk of cows which have reacted to the tuberculin test." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 44, 1903.
_________. "Milk fever: its simple and successful treatment." U.S.Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin No. 206, 1904.
__________. "The tuberculin test of cattle for tuberculosis." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 351, 1909.
__________and Geo. Byron Morse. "Necrotic stomatitis with special references to its occurrence in calves (calf diphtheria) and pigs (sore mouth)." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 67, 1905.
_______ and Henry J. Washburn. "Foot-rot of sheep its nature, cause and treatment." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 63, 1904.
_______and Henry J. Washburn. "Takosis, a contagious disease of goats: a preliminary report on its nature, cause and prevention." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 45, 1903.
_______ and Henry J Washburn. "Tuberculosis of hogs." United States Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulleti, No. 781, February 1917.
Moller, J.D. and Wedel I Holstein. "Description of a remarkable, beautiful and complete collection of type slides of diatoms mounted between the years 1886-1890. "1890.
Moore, Norman S. and Donald D. Van Slyke. "The relationships between plasma specific gravity, plasma protein content and edema in nephritis." Reprinted from The Journal of Clincal Investigation, 20 April 1930.
________and John R. Campbell. "The development of the abnormal complexes of the electrocardiogram in coronary occlusion." Reprinted from The American Heart Journal, June 1929.
Moore, Willis L. "A Report on the influence of forests on climate and on floods." House of Representatives, United States Committee on Agriculture, 1910.
Morse, George Byron. "Quail disease in the United States." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 109, 18 May 1907.
Motas, C.S. "Le role des protozoaires dans les maladies des animaux." VIII Congres International de medecine veterinaire Budapest, 1905.
Mugrage, E. R. "Diseases of animals communicable to man." Reprinted from Colorado Medicine, May 1927.
Muller, O. "Die milch-und molkereiprodukte als verbreiter der tuberkulose." VIII Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Murphy, Francis D. and Gail F. Moxon. "Diabetes mellitus and its complications: an analysis of 827 cases." Reprinted from the American Journal of Medical Sciences, September 1931.
Musser, J. H. "The Essential of the Art of Medicine." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 25 June 1898.
Myers, Buton D. "The chisma of the toad (bufo lentiginosus) and of some other vertebrates." Zeitschrift fur morphologie und anthroplogie, 1901.
Myers, Victor. "Chemical analysis of blood in general and urologic surgery." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931.
N
Nelson, Julius. "The suppression and prevention of tuberculosis of cattle and its relation to human consumption." New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 118, 30 November 1896.
________. "Report of the Biological Department of the New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station for 1894." 1895.
________. "Report of the Biological Department of the New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station for 1895." 1896.
________. "Report of the Biological Department of the New Jersey Agricultural Experiment Station for 1896." 1897.
Norgaard, Victor A. "Blackleg: its nature, cause, and prevention." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular 31, 4 March 1911.
Norgaard, Victor A. "Blackleg in the United States and the distribution of vaccine by the Bureau of Animal Industry." Reprinted from the Annual Report of the Bureau of Animal Industry, 1898.
O
Ogden, Robert Morris. "The idea of the university." School and Society, 1919.
Ohlmacher, A.P. "laboratory instruction in elementary comparative anatomy and embryology." Reprinted from the New York Medical Journal, 6 January 1894.
Olson, Carl and Alexander Zeissig. "A study of the antigenic properties of certain normal and pathological lymphoid deposits in tissues of chickens." Reprinted from The Journal of Immunology, October 1936.
Olt, Giessen. "Der krebs der haustiere." Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
P
Parker, Herman B. and George E. Beyer, et al. "Report of working party no. 1, yellow fever institute: A study of the etiology of yellow fever." United States Treasury Department, Public Health and Marine-Hospital Service, Yellow Fever Institute Bulletin No. 13, 1903.
Parkinson, John and D. Evan Bedford. "The pulmonary artery impression on the a esophagus." Reprinted from Lancet, 15 August 1931.
Parlato, Salvatore J. "The sand fly (caddis fly) as an exciting cause of allergic coryza and asthma." Reprinted from The Journal of Allergy, May 1930.
Pearce, Richard M. "The scientific method in medicine." Reprinted from Albany Medical Annals, January 1905.
Pearson, Leonard. "The effect of tuberculosis vaccination upon cattle infected with tuberculosis." Reprinted from the University of Pennsylvania Medical Bulletin, April 1905.
________ ."Tuberculosis of cattle." Pennsylvania State College Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 29, October 1894.
________ and M.P. Ravenel. "Tuberculosis of cattle." Commonweath of Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 75, 1901.
Perroncito, E. "Vaccination contre la fievre aphteuse." Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
_________. "Les substances toxiques produite par des parasites animaux." Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
Phillips, W.F.R. "Sunstroke weather of August, 1896." From the Monthly Weather Review, November 1896. Piot, J. B. "Maladies tropicales du betail observees en Egypt." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
Porter, Eugene H. "What the state shall do in the care and supervision of school children." Issued by the New York State Department of Health Division of Publicity and Education, 25 August 1913.
Pottenger, F.M. "Tuberculosis of insidious onset and of acute onset." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 7 December 1929.
Preisz, H. "Sind die tuberkelbacillen des menschen, der saugetiere und der vogel artverschieden oder nicht?" Internationaler Tierarztlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
______. "Die bakampfung der schweineseuche und schweinepest mit berucksichtigung der schutzimpfungen." Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Prescott, Samuel C. "The teaching of microbiology in colleges of United States and Canda." Reprinted from Science, 8 March 1912.
Profe, Konigl. "ausdehnung der verkehrsbeschrankungen beim auftretn der nicht unmittelbar contagiosen infectionskrankheiten, namentlich des milzbrandes." Internationaler Tierarztlicher Congress in Budapest, 1905.
Puckner, W.A. "The Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry, present and future." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 1919.
Pusch, D. "Hygiene des stalles und der streu; kritik der verschiedenen streuarten." Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
R
Ransom, B.H. "The gid parasite (coenurus cerebralis): its presence in american sheep." U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1905.
Ravenel, Mazyck R. "Intercommunicability of human and bovine tuberculosis." Medicine, July/August 1902.
__________. "Intercommunicability of human and bovine tuberculosis [ read at Pathological Society of Philadelphia mtg, 24 April 1902]." University of Pennsylvania Medical Bulletin, May 1902.
Redfield, Casper, L. "Human Heredity." April 1921.
Reed, Walter. "A comparative study of the biological characters and pathogenesis of bacillus x (Sternberg), bacillus icteroides (Sanarelli), and the hog-cholera bacilus (Salmon and Smith)." Reprinted from The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 15 December 1900.
__________and James Carroll. "The prevention of yellow fever." Reprinted from Medical Record, 26 October 1901.
__________. "the etiology of yellow fever." Reprinted from Philadelphia Medical Journal, 27 October 1900.
__________and James Carroll. "The specific cause of yellow fever.: A reply to Dr. G. Sanarelli." Reprinted from The Medical News, 9 September 1899.
Reynolds, M.H. "Bovine tuberculosis." University of Minnesota Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 51, December 1896.
Richardson, Garwood C. "The role of viosterol in pregnancy." Reprinted from the Illinois Medical Journal, June 1931.
Ricqles, A.E. "Marketing live stock." A Statement made at a hearing held at Chicago, 15-16 November 1915.
Riegler, M.P. "La morve pulmonaire et les autres formations tuberculeuses pouvant etre confondues avec elle." Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire Budapest, 1905.
Riley, C.V. "Some interrelations of plants and insects." Read before the Biological Society of Washington, 2 April 1892.
Rivers, T.M. "Viruses." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Association, 6 April 1929.
Rockl, Kaiserl. "Einheitliches muster fur die regelmassigen nachweisungen uber die verbreitung von tierseuchen." Internationaler Tierarzticher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
___________. "Studies upon the keeping quality of butter." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1904.
Rogers, L.A. "Investigations on the manufacture and storage of butter." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1906.
Ross, Mary J. "The origin and development of the gastric glands of desmognathus amblystoma and pig." Reprinted from Biological Bulletin, December 1902.
Russel, H.L. "A lesson in bovine tuberculosis." University of Wisconsis Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 114, June 1904.
________. "Tuberculosis and the tuberculin test." University of Wisconsis Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 40, July 1894.
________. "Reports on bovine tuberculosis and public health." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 53, 1904.
________. "Tuberculosis of the food-producing animals." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 38, 1906.
Rutherford, J.G. " The control of bovine tuberculosis." A paper read before Section VII. Of the International Congress on Tuberculosis at Washington, D.C., 1 October 1908.
S
Salmon, Daniel E. "Bureau of Animal Industry." Reprinted from Yearbook of Department of Agriculture, 1897.
__________. "Cornstalk disease and rabies in cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1896.
__________. "Legislation with reference to bovine tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 28, 1901.
________. "Report of the chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry for 1897." From the Secretary of Agriculture, 1897.
_______. "The tuberculin test of imported cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, 1901.
________. "Wheat as a food for growing and fattening animals." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry.
________and CH. Wardell Stiles. "Scab in sheep." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 1903.
Sanarelli, J. "The etiology and pathogenesis of yellow fever." Reprinted from International Medical Magazine, 15 January 1898.
Sanderson, Dwight. "A Survey of sickness in rural areas in Cortland County, New York." Memoir 112, 24 January 1927.
Sawin, Luther R. "Abstract: pancreatin bile salt medium for the detection of b. coli in water."
Schalk, A.F. "Undulant fever in man and its relationship to abortion disease in cattle and swine." Agricultural Experiment Station North Dakota Agricultural College, April 1930.
Schroeder, E.C. and W.E. Cotton. "Experiments concerning tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 52, pt. 3, 1905.
______ and W.E. Cotton. "Experiments with milk artifically infected with tubercle bacilli." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 86, 1906.
______ and W.E. Cotton. "The relation of tuberculous lesions to the mode of infection." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 93, 1906.
______and W.E. Cotton. "Tubercle bacilli in butter: their occurrence, vitality, and significance." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, 4 April 1908.
Schroeder, E.C. and John R. Mohler. "The tuberculin test of hogs and some methods of their infection with tuberculosis." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 88, 1906.
Seaman, W.H. "The essentials of good education, with a new classification of knowledge." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1891.
________. "The Victoria Regia." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists.
Sears, Frederick W. "Some problems in rural hygiene."
Sedgwick, T.F. "Chickens and their diseases in Hawaii." Hawaii Agricultural Experiment Station, 1901.
Sharr, E. and Opalka. "A report on the bacteriological and physical examination of lung tuberculosis in cattle." State Board of Live Stock Commissioners of Illinois Bulletin No. 5, March 1912.
Shaw, Edward L. and Lewis L. Heller. "The management of sheep on the farm." Bulletin of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 17 December 1913.
Shookhoff, Charles and Leo M. Taran. "electrocardiographic studies in infectious diseases." Reprinted from The American Journal of Diseases of Children, August 1931.
Shute, D.K. "Racial anatomical peculiarities." The American Anthropologist, April 1896.
Small, James Craig. "Streptococci in relation to rheumatic disease."
Smith, John A. "Cooperation in the control of communicable diseases among school children." New York State Department of Health, 1920.
Smith, Theobald. "Comparative pathology: Its relation to biology and medicine." Read before the Pathological Society of Philadelphia, 26 April 1900.
_______. "Injuries to cattle from swallowing pointed objects." United States Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Circular No. 8, n.d.
_______. "One of the conditions under which discontinuous sterilization may be ineffective." Reprinted from The Journal of Experimental Medicine, 1898.
_______. "Public health laboratories." Reprinted from the Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 15 November 1900.
_______. "Some biological and economic aspects of comparative pathology." Reprinted from the Edinburgh Medical Journal, April 1924.
_______. "Theories of susceptibility and resistance in relation to methods of artifical immunization." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Institute of Medicine of Chicago, 1920-1921.
_______. "Undulant fever: its relation to new problems in bacteriology and public health." Medicine: Analytical Reviews of General Medicine, Neurology and Pediatrics, May 1929.
_______. "Zur kenntniss der amerikanischen schweineseuche." Reprinted from Zeitschrift fur Hygeine, 1891.
Smithburn, K.C. and J.M Masters. "The treatment of secondary anemia (especially with various preparations of iron)." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, June 1931.
_______ and L.G. Zerfas. "The neural symptoms and signs in pernicious anemia." Reprinted from The Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry, May 1931.
Snow, William F. "Clinices for venereal diseases: Why we need them; how to develop them." Reprinted from Social Hygiene, January 1917.
Stalker, M and W.B. Niles. "Investigation of bovine tuberculosis." Iowa Agricultural College Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 29, 1895.
Stanclift. Ray Jones. "Aseptic castration of male animals." Reprinted from American Veterinary Review, July 1898.
State Charities Aid Association of New York. "Prevention of tuberculosis [ Proceedings of a Meeting held in Harmanus Bleecker Hall, Albany January 27 1908]." 1908.
Sternsberg, George M. "Disinfection and individual prophylaxis against infectious diseases." American Public Health Association Lomb Prize Essay, 1900.
Stiles, Charles W. "Bau u. entwicklungsgeschichte v. pentastomum proboscideum rud. Und pentastomum subcylindricum dies." Reprinted from Zeitschrift dur wissenschaftliche Zoologique, 1891.
_______. "Notes on parasites." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, February 1892.
_______. "Notes sure les parasites." Reprintyed from the Bulletin de la Societe Zoologique, 1891.
_______. "Sur la biologie des linguatules." Reprinted from the Comptes rendus des senaces de la Societe de Biologie, May 1891.
Stone, Winthrop E. "The carbohydrates of wheat, maize, flour, and bread, and the action of enzymic ferments upon starches of different origin." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 34, 1896.
_______. "Dietary studies at Purdue University, Lafayette, IND., in 1895." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 32, 1896.
Stragnell, Gregory. "Clinical use of female sex hormone." Reprinted from Clinical Medicine and Surgery, February 1932.
Stroud, Bert. B. "If an 'isthmus rhombencephali' why not an 'isthmus prosencephali'?" Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, December 1899.
_______. "The mammalian cerebellum, part 1." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, July 1895.
_______. "A new head-rest for the removal of the human brain." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, May 1900.
_______. "Notes on the appendix." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of Americin Anatomists, December 1897.
_______. "On the anatomy of the anus." Reprinted from Annals of Surgery, July 1896.
_______. "A preliminary account of the degenerations in the central nervous system of frogs deprived of the cerebrum." Cornell reprint?
Swingle, Walter T. "Bordeaux mixture: its chemistry, physical properties, and toxic effects on fungi and algae." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Division of Vegetable Physiology and Pathology, Bulletin No. 9, 1896.
Szegedy-Maszak, E. de. "Les dernieres experiences sur la transmission des maladies animales chez l'homme (en tenant specialement compte des differents metiers)." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
Szpilman, Josef. "Bekampfung und tilgung der wutkrankheit." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
T
Taylor, Thomas. "Food products.-III." Reprinted with revision from the Report of the Secretary of Agriculture for 1891, 1893.
_______. "Report of the Chief of the Division of Microscopy for 1893." U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1894.
Taylor, Walter J. "The agglutination and precipitating power of glandered and non glandered blood serum in diagnosis." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Veterinary Medical Association, September 1907.
Todd, L. C. "Comparative study of bacillus anthracis-symptomatici and allied organisms with respect to gas-production." Parke-Davis Research Laboratory, Reprint No. 118, 1917.
U
Underhill, Frank. P. "The alleged toxin of burned skin." Reprinted fom The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931.
V
Vaillant, D. E. "La bacillosine." 3rd Congres Français de Climatotherapie & D'Hygiene Urbaine, April 1907.
Van Dine, D. L. "Insecticides for use in Hawaii." Hawaii Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 3, 1903.
Van Es, L. "Bovine tuberculosis." North Dakota Agricultural College, Government Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 77, July 1907.
_______. "Glanders." North Dakota Agricultural College, Government Agricultural Experiment Station of North Dakota, Bulletin No. 85, September 1909.
_______. and H. M. Martin. "The immunizing value of commercial vaccines and bacterins against herorrhagic septicemia." Agricultural Experiment Station, University oof Nebraska, Lincoln, Research Bulletin 17, June 1920.
Van Slyke, D. D. et al. "Observations on the courses of different types of Bright's Disease, and on the resultant changes in renal anatomy." Reprinted from Medicine, September 1930.
Van Slyke, L. L. And J. C. Baker. "Conditions causing variation in the reaction of freshly-drawn milk." New York Agricultural Experiment Station, Technical Bulletin No. 70, June 1919.
Voltz, W. "Stallfutterung und weidegang vom biologischen gesichtpunkte." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
Voorhees, Edward B. "Food and nutrition investigations in New Jersey in 1895 and 1896." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 35, 1896.
W
Wait, Charles E. "Dietary studies at the University of Tennessee in 1895. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 29, 1896.
Wallace, A. W. "Sino-auricular block" Reprinted from American Heart Journal, April 1930.
Ward, Herbert C. "Blackleg agressin." Reprinted from Journal of American Veterinary Medical Association, July 1919.
Ward, Archibald R. "Fowl cholera." University of California, College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 156, April 1904.
_______. "Tuberculosis in fowls." University of California College of Agriculture /Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 161, 1904.